# **Sudeep Basnet**

www.linkedin.com/in/sudeepbasnet/

Address: 722 North Center Street,

Naperville, IL, US

Phone: **402-617-1329** 

Email: sudbasnet10@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Dedicated, career-oriented individual with 4+ years of professional experience, interested in Software Development tied to Data Analytics and Artificial Intelligence. Master's in Computer Science. Redesigned codebase and automated data-processing at previous employment resulting in gains around 40-60%, was awarded for performance and teamwork.

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming:** Python, Java, R, JavaScript, SQL, HTML/CSS

Other Technical: GIT, Systems Administration (UNIX), Data Analysis, Predictive Modelling, Matplotlib, Bokeh,

Django, Node, React, Project Management, JIRA, Database Development

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant** | Jan 2017 - Aug 2019

<u>University of Nebraska – Lincoln (UNL)</u>

- **Agent-based Simulation Design.** Developed an ABM simulation model to simulate and predict social unrest on a geographic and temporal scale, in *Repast Java*. (<a href="https://github.com/sudbasnet/SocialUnrestMAS">https://github.com/sudbasnet/SocialUnrestMAS</a>)
- Data visualization, development and management of PHP backed web application, uses HTML/CSS, Knockout[S, Google Maps JavaScript API and MySQL database. (https://cse.unl.edu/~surge/)
- **Research Scientist.** Utilized agent-based modelling to study social unrest built on behavioral social science models. Developed a scalable variant of DBSCAN algorithm in *Python* to cluster GIS (spatiotemporal) data. Published a research paper. (<a href="https://github.com/sudbasnet/spatiotemporal-kdTree">https://github.com/sudbasnet/spatiotemporal-kdTree</a>)
- **Data Mining, Data Analysis and Data Management** using *Python, R* and *Java*, utilizing parallel computing on Nebraska's second-fastest High-Performance Computing servers.
- **Prepared C++ Tutorials and Lab Assignments** of Network Simulations in ns3 to teach about TCP, DP, IP, ICMP, MAC, OSI layers.

## Sr. Software Engineer - Data Operations | July 2012 - Dec 2016

Cotiviti Nepal Pvt. Ltd. | Kathmandu, Nepal | (Subsidiary of COTIVITI INC, Waltham MA)

- **Developed** *Java* based application and *Oracle* databases (PL/SQL), stored procedures, functions and triggers to create ETL scripts, tools, queries and applications used for healthcare data management, data validation, statistical report generation, and program validation.
- **Data Analysis** of US healthcare data (HIPAA protected medical data) in Oracle (*PL/SQL*). Applied statistical, predictive modeling and data mining techniques to support analytical solutions.
- Led multiple teams of Software Engineers through different projects for two years.
- **Optimized** several large clients by 40 60% in processing time, by implementing parallel processes and redesigning backend jobs (*PLSQL* and *Java*).
- Awarded with "Team of the Quarter 2015", and "Verisk Way to Go -2014" for performance.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science, Computer Science (GPA: 3.8) | Jan 2017 - August 2019

<u>University of Nebraska – Lincoln, NE, USA</u>

- MS Thesis: Analysis of Social Unrest Events using Agent-based Simulation and Spatiotemporal clustering
- Relevant Courses:

Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Data Structures, Machine Learning, Systems Administration, GIS

## OTHER INTERESTS AND PERSONAL PROJECTS

Personal Website (work ongoing) http://www.sbasnet.com/

Built in MVC framework using Django; front-end with React.js and Phaser III HTML5 game framework.

Machine Learning and AI https://github.com/sudbasnet/machine-learning

https://github.com/sudbasnet/NeuralNetwork

HaliteIII Online AI Challenge (top 10%) https://github.com/sudbasnet/halite3